Jennifer Berry

Frontend Developer

Tel: 07999 298 382

Location: London NW10

Email: JenBerryMail@Gmail.com
Portfolio: portfolio.jenberry.co.uk
Code Examples: github.com/JenBerry

Summary

I am a Frontend Developer, with 4 years experience, looking for freelance/contract work. My focus is in responsive HTML, CSS and JavaScript with various libraries and frameworks. I have experience with CMS, backend and database technologies, while also having an intuitive eye for good Design and User Experience, so I can be useful in translating between designers and developers.

Primary Skills

Development: Responsive HTML(5), CSS(3)/SASS/LESS, JavaScript with

jQuery, Bootstrap and Foundation layout frameworks, React.js & Redux, Django & Meteor.js. MySQL/Mongo databases. Node, gulp, git version control, command line interface. Linux. Also the Qt UI

development framework with Qt Quick/QML

Design: PhotoShop & GIMP, Inkscape, Illustrator, Scribus, Hand drawings.

Education

2006-2009 Peterhouse, University of Cambridge

2:1 BA Hons Natural Sciences

1st year: Physics, Maths, Computer Science, Evolution&Behavior 2nd year: Physics, Animal Biology, Experimental Psychology

3rd year: Zoology

Employment & Experience

Freelance Frontend developer since Oct 2013: List of projects

Apr 2016 Wunderman: Website for Huawei phone launch

Last minute adjustments and bug fixes for a website launching the Huawei P9 and P9P phones. HTML, SASS and jQuery on the front end, and also working with gulp.js and Node to build the site.

Jan 2016 Bond & Coyne: Responsive Frontend development

Taking Illustrator designs and turning them into responsive frontend

HTML templates using the Twig templating engine and the

Foundation layout framework with SASS. Also making use of CSS3 animations, and using jQuery for interactivity. Templates were to be

integrated into the Craft CMS.

Nov 2014 - Jun 2015

Quru: Website and responsive emails for Bonhams.com

Redevelop the existing website, to be fully responsive across devices. Use of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, MooTools, and interfacing with Angular JS and Django. Development of a responsive HTML email that works across all major email clients. Testing using Litmus.com. General maintenance and bug fixing.

Oct 2014 PMC Healthcare

Adding interactive javascript elements to a video based educational website. Use of JSPlumb, PopcornJS, and JQuery JavaScript libraries.

Mar 2014 Access Pay

HTML, CSS and JQuery. Developed static demo website from photoshop designs using the Foundation layout framework. Use of Font Awesome, HighchartsJS, PowertipJS.

Nov-Dec 2013 U-dox creative ltd: website for Defected.com

Finishing/bug-fixing an e-commerce website for the record label: Defected.com. Using Django web framework, Oscar e-commerce framework, and Bootstrap layout framework. Coding in HTML, LESS, and JavaScript. Working with git version control, virtual environments, and Redmine project management.

Oct-Nov 2013 GiveMeTap

Improving the website of a startup. Using Ruby on Rails, Shopify CMS, and google maps API.

Previous experience

Jun 2012 - **1 year traveling around the world: Europe, Russia, Australasia**Jul 2013 Backpacking, hitch hiking, camping, couch surfing. Requires ability to adapt and improvise. Improved my confidence in new situations, and my ability to connect with strangers.

Feb 2011 - User Experience Designer: Domino Printing Sciences

Jun 2012 Designed and developed a UI for production-line coding&marking printers running on low-spec hardware. Intuitive UI, common across several different printer technologies and two screen sizes.

Developed using Qt, a C++ cross-platform application framework, and I coded in its frontend language: QML, with JavaScript.

Jun - Dec 2010 Clerical Assistant & Integrated Designer: Orchard Park Community Council

I created their website with Joomla!, designed their logo, event posters, promotional leaflets, and newsletters. Use of Scribus, OpenOffice Drawing, and Inkscape. I was the first point of contact for the Community council, required communicating on the phone and in person with a wide range of people, and managing the bookings for the hire of the Community Centre.

Jun 09 -Jun 10 Webmaster: Cambridge Rock Society

Updated the Django and MySQL back end of their website, redesigned and developed the frontend with XHTML and CSS. Use of git version control, SSH and other command line tools.

2008-2010 Design projects during university

- Cambridge University Scientific Society: Graphic Design of posters to advertise weekly talks during term time
- Weevil Publications: Cover artist. Creation of background artworks for the front page of their termly magazine
- Russel Laboratory, genetics department at Cambridge University. Logo design.

Referees:

Client: Jason Hancock

Bond & Coyne, 335 Canterbury Court, 1-3 Brixton Road, London, SW9 6DE 020 3567 1100, jason@bondandcoyne.co.uk

Client: Roland Whitehead, CEO Quru Ltd, Somerset House, Strand, London, WC2R 1LA 020 7160 2888, roland@guru.com

Employer: Andy Barrett, Technical Product Specialist Domino Printing Sciences, Bar Hill, Cambridge, CB23 8TU 01945 785549 ext 4205, Andy.Barrett@domino-uk.com